Ms. Xu,
what brings you here today?
My son encouraged me to come.
I also hope
this matter
can be resolved as soon as possible.
If you have any questions,
just ask.
Let's start with something off-topic.
Your husband, Li Shaofeng,
passed away three years ago.
Have you ever thought about moving out?
My child's school is close
to my in-laws' house.
It's just for convenience.
Then why did you move out recently?
After all,
so much has happened in that old house.
The child is still young,
and I was quite scared too,
so I just
moved out.
Your neighbors
said your parents-in-law
didn't get along well.
We'd like to hear your thoughts.
They
indeed didn't get along well.
But after all, they've been together
for so many years.
It's normal for them to bicker.
It's quite normal.
Why put up with it for so many years,
but not this time?
How should I know?
It's between the two of them.
I can't explain it.
Did they start arguing
when you were at home?
No.
Are you sure?
We already have evidence
proving that
you were present
when your parents-in-law were arguing.
At 4:23 p.m. that day,
your parents-in-law had a dispute.
You entered the residential compound
at 4:24 p.m.
It takes no more than three minutes
from the gate to your door.
When you got home,
they were still arguing.
I
was in my room at the time.
had my headphones on.
I...
didn't know what was happening outside.
Then what were they doing
when you left?
I'll tell you the truth.
When I got home,
my father-in-law was already dead.
And then?
Then,
I was really scared at the time.
I didn't know what to do.
I-
I just
took the kid and ran.
Then why didn't you call the police,
instead of waiting for your mother-in-law
to turn herself in?
Call the police?
I mean it.
My mind was a total mess
when I thought about
what happened in my family.
I really didn't know
what I was thinking at the time.
So I really didn't think that much.
Then why do you think Zhou Yumei
delayed calling the police?
How would I know what she was thinking?
Maybe
because
s-
she might have hesitated.
After all,
not everyone
can just turn themselves in,
right?
Did she hesitate,
or did she intentionally wait for you
to leave the neighborhood
to hide your presence at the time?
How would I know what she was thinking?
You should ask her that question.
Then let's talk about the murder weapon.
Zhou Yumei said she was cut by a knife,
but we didn't find her blood
on it.
So we suspect
the knife that cut Zhou Yumei
and the one that killed Li Hongkang
are not the same.
Where is that knife?
How
would I know where the knife is?
What
exactly are you trying to ask?
That's what you get
for not listening to me.
Bozhou,
Come here.
Go downstairs and play for a while.
I'll come find you later.
You might not know this,
but Li Bozhou called me yesterday.
He said he saw his grandpa
hitting his grandma
and was very scared.
He also said his mom is a good person
and asked us not to arrest her.
A child's sense of good and evil
is simple and pure.
The fact that he called us
behind your back
shows he knows exactly what's going on.
Xu Nianqiu,
this will only end if you tell
the truth.
Only then can he live a normal life.
You wouldn't want your child
to live with a shadow over his heart
for the rest of his life,
right?
I'll talk.
The person who killed Li Hongkang
wasn't my mother-in-law.
It was me.
Go downstairs and play for a while.
I'll come find you later.
I told you...
Did
I kill someone?
I
killed someone.
What are you doing?
Remember this.
You just came back to pick something up.
All of this happened after you left.
I killed him.
You know nothing.
Are we clear?
I can't leave you alone.
I won't...
Stop talking.
Bozhou can live without a grandma,
but he can't lose his mom.
Hurry!
Hurry up!
Go!
Hurry.
Didn't I tell you to go downstairs?
What are you doing here?
My mother-in-law took the blame for me.
I let her down.
You took the murder weapon
from the kitchen.
Then tell me,
where exactly is that knife?
I really don't know anything
about a knife.
I wasn't paying attention
to that at the time.
Before the murder,
Zhou Yumei was in close contact with a man
named Lu Minchuan.
Did you know
that Lu Minchuan is actually Li Hongkang?
I knew.
I've known about it all along.
That day,
I went to buy study materials for Bozhou
and saw my father-in-law
at the bookstore too.
I didn't think much of it at the time.
Who are you chatting with?
Have an apple.
Nianqiu,
have you read this book?
I asked you to look at the photo.
Who told you to look at anything else?
That night,
I saw that Lu Minchuan
sent my mother-in-law
the exact same photo.
Do you think this is a coincidence?
Of course I've thought about it.
But
I pulled a note
out of his pocket
with a poem on it.
I didn't expect
that a couple of days later,
Lu Minchuan would send
the same poem to my mother-in-law.
So do you still think
this is a coincidence?
Then did you tell your mother-in-law
about Lu Minchuan's true identity?
Of course I did.
But she didn't believe me at all.
No matter what I told her,
she just blindly chose
to believe that Lu Minchuan.
She just loves him with all her heart.
She won't listen to anything I say.
After retiring,
Li Hongkang took pleasure
in controlling my mother-in-law.
At home,
he beats and curses at my mother-in-law.
Then he turns around
and plays Lu Minchuan online
to toy with her feelings.
He's a total psycho.
The worse Li Hongkang
treats your mother-in-law in real life,
the better the online Lu Min
treats her.
Your mother-in-law needs
Lu Minchuan's emotional support.
She won't believe the truth.
What about you?
Did you have any direct
or indirect conflicts
with Li Hongkang?
I guess you could say so.
Previously,
Li Hongkang took
Shao Feng's 800,000 compensation.
I always thought
he was saving it
for his grandson.
But I recently found out
he lost it all in the stock market.
So was your action
out of desperation,
or was it some kind of emotional release?
Although I resented him,
what happened that day
was truly an accident,
a coincidence.
If I hadn't stepped in,
my mother-in-law would be dead.
I regret it.
I killed someone.
I really regret it.
Especially when I think about my son
having no one to take care of him,
I regret it even more.
Zhou Yumei stayed at the scene
the whole time.
She should know exactly
where that knife is.
I suggest
we interrogate Zhou Yumei again.
But in her condition, will she cooperate?
She probably will.
Xu Nianqiu has already confessed.
And 3D modeling has reconstructed
the crime scene.
There's no point
in her hiding it anymore.
Tell you what,
let's discuss the conviction
and sentencing first.
Is Xu Nianqiu killing Li Hongkang
excessive self-defense
or manslaughter?
I actually think...
We should consider
Xu Nianqiu's subjective malice
towards Li Hongkang.
Her hatred for him was real.
So we can't rule out
intentional homicide
in the heat of passion.
Her stab was the fatal wound.
Technically speaking,
the force and angle
look more like a deliberate attack.
But Zhou Yumei's life was in danger
at the time.
Objectively, Xu Nianqiu's action
was to save her mother-in-law.
This should be classified as
manslaughter under excessive self-defense.
I suggest we be a bit more lenient
with the sentencing.
Xu Nianqiu's actions did result in death,
but her motive was to save someone.
In judicial practice,
such cases are mostly ruled as
excessive self-defense.
We must uphold the law
without losing our humanity.
What about Zhou Yumei?
Her stab was clearly to finish him off.
The purpose was very clear,
to kill Li Hongkang.
So I think
Zhou Yumei committed intentional homicide.
We also need to consider
other circumstances comprehensively.
We can't just focus on
the finishing blow.
Then she--
Aren't you going to discuss
her original intention?
Kaixin,
Zhou Yumei's purpose
in finishing off Li Hongkang
was indeed clear.
Okay.
All right,
let's drop it for now.
We can analyze this in detail
along with other cases.
No rush.
Here,
I'd like to say a few words.
What we hold in our hands
are not cold legal provisions,
but the power to determine
life and death...
the yardstick for distinguishing
right from wrong.
The law has a bottom line
that cannot be crossed,
but human warmth and empathy
should also be the attitude
of our justice system.
Xu Nianqiu had the original intention
of saving someone,
and Zhou Yumei
has a background of long-term abuse.
All of these
should be taken into consideration
for sentencing.
What we need to punish is
the act of excessive defense
and overkilling,
rather than driving desperate people
into a corner.
We must make criminals pay the price,
while also letting the public
feel the fairness
and compassion of the law.
This is what we should do.
Xu Nianqiu has already
confessed to the crime.
Is there any point in hiding it?
We have one last question for you.
Where exactly is the knife
that cut you?
I don't know what knife
you're talking about.
This video
is a reconstruction based on
your and Xu Nianqiu's statements,
as well as the crime scene investigation.
Your concealment
is meaningless now.
Is this
Bozhou?
He...
He knows everything,
doesn't he?
Bozhou,
Grandma is so sorry.
The situation is clear.
We can't let the child get hurt anymore.
I hope you can tell us
where the knife is.
Got it.
Thanks.
The police said
they found the knife
cleaned by Zhou Yumei in the locker,
and detected traces
of her blood on it.
Then why didn't she just
dispose of the knife?
Her motive was simple.
She just wanted to cover for Xu Nianqiu.
Zhou Yumei's ultimate goal
was for her grandson, Li Bozhou.
Speaking of Li Bozhou,
didn't he visit our office before?
He was really interested
in your Rubik's cube,
so I let him play with it for a while.
Indeed.
He's quite smart.
He solved one side
after just a short while.
I couldn't do that when I was a kid.
He's so young
to have suffered such a tragic experience.
And without a guardian,
imagine how traumatized he must be.
Li Bozhou has already been placed
in a welfare home.
How about this?
Since everyone is here today
and we have time,
let's go visit him together.
Sounds good.
The child has been adapting
well these past two days,
but he doesn't talk much.
Seeing someone familiar today
is a good thing for him.
Let's go in.
Kids,
look,
I brought you so many yummy treats.
Do you like this?
Thank you.
Here's a pink one.
Bozhou,
Look.
A chocolate bar.
I like it.
This is for you.
When I was little,
I also went through
some very difficult times.
Whenever I felt like I couldn't hold on,
I would spin this a few times.
to calm yourself down.
Your mom
specifically asked us
to bring this to you.
She has heard you like
playing with this toy.
She is really happy.
I hope it brings you a lot of joy
during this time.
Thank you, Ms. Fang.
We'll start psychological intervention
as soon as possible
and assign a dedicated social worker
for long-term follow-up.
However,
we need to designate
a long-term external contact.
The child has no suitable relatives
around right now.
If you have any questions,
feel free to contact us anytime.
Also,
considering the public opinion,
we hope to transfer him
to another school as soon as possible
for a better environment.
Meanwhile,
his privacy must be protected.
Rest assured,
we will communicate with the school.
Thank you for your trouble.